<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>My Books</title><link>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/</link><description>Recent content on My Books</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>My Name</copyright><atom:link href="https://github.io/pluriscient/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/answers-to-big-questions-hawking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/answers-to-big-questions-hawking/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/book-summaries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/book-summaries/</guid><description>Introduction I&amp;rsquo;ll start with an introduction of my general ambition with this document, which is quite simply to record a personal summary and reflection for each of the books I&amp;rsquo;ve read or listened to. I have some catching up to do, and I&amp;rsquo;ll start with outlining A. Why I&amp;rsquo;m doing this, and B. Which books I still have to do this for. Then I&amp;rsquo;ll start with at least 2 of the books within this same paper before creating a structure, because I know from myself that I can get quite distracted/ dwell away from the main point if I do that first.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/breath-nestor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/breath-nestor/</guid><description>Breath: The New Science of a Lost Art (James Nestor) Great first parts, latter part became a bit too much pseudo-sciencey for my liking.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/echt-geleend/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/echt-geleend/</guid><description>Bij deze heb ik op 29 feb. besloten om 550 euro voor de huur van de maand echt te lenen van DUO.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/elegant-universe-greene/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/elegant-universe-greene/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/guns-germs-steel-diamond/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/guns-germs-steel-diamond/</guid><description>Guns, Germs, and Steel: The fates of Human Societies (Jared Diamond) A really different look on history, dissecting history, geology, and biology in order to find out why it is not the Native Americans but the Europeans that colonised the world.
While his conclusions answer many questions they also ask us many other ones anew.
In essence Jared says that it is mostly the ability to spread geographically that determines speed of growth, along with basic advantages such as tamable creatures, not (lack of) intelligence among other peoples, something I can definitely agree with.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/hbr-10-new-machine-age-2018/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/hbr-10-new-machine-age-2018/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/how-to-munroe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/how-to-munroe/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/meditations-aurelius/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/meditations-aurelius/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/mensen-deugen-bregman/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/mensen-deugen-bregman/</guid><description>De meeste mensen deugen (Rutger Bregman) I&amp;rsquo;m going to be honest here, I never expected to be putting a Dutch book on this list. Not because I can&amp;rsquo;t read Dutch (I have a good grasp of the intricacies of the Dutch language as a native), but because I had grown to hate Dutch literature in all of its forms over the years in high school where I was forced to read and analyze literature that I intensely disliked, which took away my interest.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/mindsets-dweck/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/mindsets-dweck/</guid><description>Mindsets (Carol S. Dweck) [[mindsets]] Maybe a bit cheating but I&amp;rsquo;ll first copy my summary from last week here:
In the book Mindsets, we learn about the two different mindsets people can have in a field: a fixed mindset where nothing can change and one must prove time and time again that the &amp;rsquo;natural ability&amp;rsquo; was high enough, and the growth mindset, where everything is capable of growth if one tries hard enough in the right way.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/moonwalking-with-einstein/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/moonwalking-with-einstein/</guid><description>Moonwalking with Einstein (todo author)</description></item><item><title/><link>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/nearly-everything-bryson/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/nearly-everything-bryson/</guid><description>A short History of Nearly Everything, Bill Bryson This is Bryson&amp;rsquo;s attempt to explore the natural sciences from their roots to their current state, mostly through the people that have advanced it throughout the past few centuries. I was expecting a different kind of book when I first received it, with a cover indicative of engineering and design. Expectant of a descriptive explanation of how everything in the world works, I instead opened it to find an entirely different perspective on the sciences.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/never-split-the-difference-voss/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/never-split-the-difference-voss/</guid><description>Never Split the Difference - Chris Voss This book is an introduction into the theory of negotiation. It starts</description></item><item><title/><link>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/origin-of-wealth-beinhocker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/origin-of-wealth-beinhocker/</guid><description>The Origin of Wealth, Eric D. Beinhocker I received this book from my father for my 15th birthday because he &amp;lsquo;could not read the small letters&amp;rsquo;. Now, 6 years later, I can consider myself part of a set of readers extraordinary in their due diligence and dedication for having finished this book. While written as a popular introduction on the book, this 500-page literary work engulves one in stats surrounding economic theory, both the incumbent current champion of the day, &amp;lsquo;Traditional Market Theory&amp;rsquo;, as has been developed from Adam Smith onwards, and a &amp;rsquo;new&amp;rsquo; theory of complexity economics that finds its basis in the concept of evolution instead of assumptions on rationality.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/philip-and-alexander-goldsworthy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/philip-and-alexander-goldsworthy/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/promised-land-obama/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/promised-land-obama/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/range-epstein/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/range-epstein/</guid><description>Range: Why Generalists thrive in a Specialized World (David Epstein) This was one of those nice reads that makes everything it says stand out as well-founded. The main point that the author tries to make is that you should not specialize (early), as it can be just overvuew that you gain by keeping a broader perspective that allows you to succeed. He illustrates this with several topics: Sports, Art, Music, Study (choice), and (academic) research.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/speak-science-benamran/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/speak-science-benamran/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/talking-to-strangers-gladwell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/talking-to-strangers-gladwell/</guid><description>Talking to Strangers (Malcolm Gladwell) I did not expect the content I got when I read this book. I expected it to be about some common fallacies we possess and tips on how to deal with them, but instead got a rollercoaster ride emotionally about how some fundamentally human flaws about understanding others contribute to a lot of despairingly solvable problems in our society. If I were to give the most powerful one to realise that would be the power of coupling, how certain actions are linked quite tightly with their environment and context.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/think-again-grant/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/think-again-grant/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/thinking-fast-and-slow-kahnemann/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/thinking-fast-and-slow-kahnemann/</guid><description>Thinking, Fast and Slow (Daniel Kahnemann) This book tells us the story of three pairs of (opposing) entities: That of System 1 and System 2, Econs and humans, and the experiencing and remembering selves. System 1 and 2 are personalisations of two kinds of ways our brain approaches the world, through an intuitive understanding of the world and speedy decisions (system 1), and a slower, (more) rational system 2, which monitors system 1 and may take over when it doesn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;lsquo;agree&amp;rsquo; or is triggered.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/u-thrive-lerner/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/u-thrive-lerner/</guid><description>U Thrive: How to Succeed in College (and Life) (Dan Lerner, Alan Daniel Schlechter) While a bit too assertive to my taste, I listened to this book and found it containing a lot of the insights that I had collected over the years of reading self-development books as well as some new ones which I enjoyed very much. Good starter for anyone, though you should always take things with a grain of salt.</description></item><item><title>21 lessons for the 21st century</title><link>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/21-lessons-harari/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/21-lessons-harari/</guid><description>21 Lessons for the 21st Century Rather should be named less optimistically. More =: What could possibly wrong!? It&amp;rsquo;s full of problems that we as a species are going to run headfirst into in the upcoming century.</description></item><item><title>A better world</title><link>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/a-better-world/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/a-better-world/</guid><description>A better world Writing is more engaging to me than typing but I do not possess access to a notbeook atm so am consigned to cramping my hands on the plane.
One of the major goals in my life, as it is in that of many others, is to improve the world. At first glance this is quite a naive goal, and I must admit that as of this moment, it is.</description></item><item><title>Algorithms to Live by</title><link>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/algorithms-christian/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/algorithms-christian/</guid><description>Algorithms to Live by (Brian Christian and Tom Griffiths) Very interesting fresh perpective from computer science on other aspects of life, from sorting to choosing a girl.</description></item><item><title>Loserthink (Scott Adams)</title><link>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/loserthink-adams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.io/pluriscient/books/summaries/loserthink-adams/</guid><description>Loserthink (Scott Adams) Never thought I&amp;rsquo;d be reading a book that puts Trump in a mostly positive light and not feel like the author doesn&amp;rsquo;t know anything. Scott Adams made for a very interesting read about his concept of losethink. Loserthink being basically anything that doesn&amp;rsquo;t help you, society, or your current conversation in any meaningful way.
Summary of learning points Adams&amp;rsquo; approach was to go through the &amp;lsquo;minds&amp;rsquo; of particular professions who each have particular methods for perceiving the world and seeing what we can learn from them.</description></item></channel></rss>